all right so here we have a satellite
that is located a distance of 7 r r
being the radius of the planet or Earth
in this case um and it wants us to find
the local acceleration due to gravity
for the satellite all right so this
one's pretty straightforward this is
just a ratio problem here uh here I have
my yellow chart surface and altitude or
before and after if you like one and two
A and B whatever it is you want to use
but have a reference point okay so here
my reference point is going to be at the
surface because I know the generic
function for acceleration neutral
gravity at the surface of the planet is
G mass of the Earth and then the race of
the earth square and then once I know
that I can set up the right side of the
uh chart here pretty quickly so here I
call it G new or the acceleration due to
gravity or the local acceleration due to
gravity for the satellite which is just
GM Earth over the radius
square uh but radius is being used kind
of vake here okay so really at the end
of the day it's the distance from Center
to Center but the diagram shows you
already that this Arrow here watch my
cursor please so here's planet Earth and
blue the distance given to you in the
schematic actually starts at the center
of the planet and it goes all the way to
the orbit of the satellite so in this
particular case 7R already includes the
radius of the planet so therefore the
distance from Center to where the orbit
is or where the Salah is is given a 7R
so therefore in the denominator I would
just substitute in 7R but use
parenthesis if you don't use parth
parentheses you'll forget to square the
coefficient 7 so it's important to use
parenthesis here so because there is an
exponent two I want to shoot that
exponent to the seven I'm also going to
introduce that uh excuse me um
distribute that exponent to the r as
well so essentially the numerator stays
the same except the bottom 7 square is
49 and then R square is R square here uh
hopefully you've seen my other videos
you can learn how to factor out
coefficients just to make things look a
little nicer you don't have to if you
know what you're doing but I like to
make it look a little nicer I notice the
only really thing difference between the
left side and the right side here is the
49 in the
denominator well because the 49
denominator I can just Factor It Out by
putting under a one and then gm/ r² I'll
keep that as the same term because on
the left side of the chart acceleration
due to gravity at the surface of the
planet is given by G mass of the earth
and the radius of the planet Square so I
notice here I have the same term here g
f Earth over r s so I want to highlight
the same
term therefore what I can do is I can
substitute out g m r² for lowercase G at
the surface of the planet which in this
case is Earth which is 9.8 so therefore
I can substitute out this whole entire
highlighted term g m e over r² for G but
then now it's the same thing 1 * G is
just G and then G over 49 G got
substituted out for 9.8 and then 9.8 ID
4.9 will give you an answer of 0.2 m/s
squar okay and that's it for this one
this one's pretty straightforward all
right good luck stay ready don't be back